hey guys let's talk about some log
derivatives so it says find dydx when Y
is equal to Ln of root X I think this is
a beautiful one first I just want to
rewrite the root X as x to the one-half
power so now we're ready to take the
derivative so we have a function inside
of a function so we're going to do chain
rule so first we're going to work with
the natural log the derivative of
natural log of anything is 1 over that
something and then because of chain rule
we're going to multiply by the
derivative of what's inside here so the
derivative of x to the one half we're
going to bring the one-half in front and
it's going to be x to the and then we do
one half minus one which gives us
negative one half this piece right here
the one-half exponent means it's going
to be the square root of x and then this
x the negative one half means we're
going to have square root in the
denominator so it's going to be one over
two root X because the 2 right here so
this 2 is left on bottom and root x
times root X is equal to X and that is
the answer to the question d y d x is 1
over 2x so this really isn't super
difficult but if you don't know what
you're doing it definitely can be tricky